I am Ms. Frieren's student.
You pass.
Next.
You're there like the wind
Closing your eyes at sunset
I wonder what's on your mind
Beyond Journey's End
With your eyelids open
Your eyes shone like glass
It faintly smelled like a sunny day
Clear up the sky, let flowers bloom
Bloom and blame it on the sunny sky
Even the rain, when it stops
Will make you shine in the sunlight
Calm the stirring sounds in my heart
We go like the sunny wind
Go on and fly over that cloud
Further and further away
Denken the Imperial Mage.
I know all about you.
I'm honored.
A self-made military mage who rose to be
the most influential in the northern lands.
It's an oft-heard heroic tale.
Honestly, I wish I could've met you
when you were still young,
full of drive and ambition.
I have no interest in burnt-out ashes.
Or so I believed.
Do you feel differently now?
When you saw me, you thought about
how you'd fight me, didn't you?
Only for a moment.
I immediately abandoned the idea.
You pass. There's still a fire in you.
Normally it wouldn't even occur
to someone to fight me.
Next.
You pass.
What? But we haven't even spoken yet.
Do we need to?
I guess not.
Next.
Is this some kind of joke?
What do you mean?
This is the first-class mage exam.
What kind of idiot never even sets foot
into the examination grounds?
As you can see, my flesh-and-blood
body is here, too.
I wouldn't want to be disqualified.
Throughout the exam period, your actual
body never left your hometown.
Are you enjoying some tea right now?
I'm surprised.
Not even Übel noticed.
You've got guts. You pass.
Next.
You're Wirbel, captain of
the Northern Magic Corps.
Of the second-class mages I know,
you're the most combat-oriented.
With a single look, you realized
you couldn't beat me in battle.
But that wasn't a judgment made out of fear.
An idiot prone to picking fights he can't win
wouldn't even make it to second-class mage.
That's true.
Tell me, what's your favorite spell?
Magic is a tool for killing.
I neither like nor dislike any spells.
You pass.
Next.
What did you think when you saw me?
Um, I thought you were small and cute.
What's wrong with this year's test-takers?
You pass.
Sense.
My apologies. We do have
a bumper crop this year.
I failed.
There's always next time.
Stop following me.
Three years, huh?
Ms. Frieren, I passed.
Well done.
Frieren.
I made it this far because of you two.
Finally, I can visit a certain grave
in my hometown.
I see.
Hey, Fern.
Have you decided yet?
I'd like—
Old man, I want these.
Well, well.
Don't be shy. Eat up.
When I was young, I hardly
ever got to eat sweet things.
Thank you.
What's going on here?
Have some, young man.
Thanks, old man.
Who is he?
Mr. Denken the Imperial Mage.
An imperial mage?
You mean he's a noble?!
I'm sorry for speaking so casually to you.
It's fine. I came to this city
as a mage like any other.
But you shouldn't feel obliged
to treat a stranger like me...
I have no other use for my money.
There must be something.
He's right. Don't you have grandchildren?
I have no children or grandchildren.
My wife passed away when
I was in my mid-twenties.
She was always sickly.
She was the daughter of a frontier noble
of the Northern Plateau who was
defeated in a political dispute.
Back then, I was in need of both
wealth and influence.
Those were the only ways I knew to save her.
When Serie established the
Continental Magic Association
and began offering the privilege,
it was just after my wife had already passed.
I'd never felt more powerless.
It's ironic. These days, I could
order entire nations around.
Fern.
For me, magic was only ever a tool
to resolve political disputes.
Tell Frieren she reminded me
of how fun magic can be.
The whole reason I became a mage was because
I admired her deeds in the party of heroes.
You should tell her that yourself.
I'm sure she'd be glad to hear it.
You're right. That's what I'll do.
The magical city of Äußerst didn't disappoint.
I bought a bunch of good grimoires.
Hey, old woman.
You want those in this basket, right?
How could you just ignore her?
Honestly, I did think about it a little.
Just a little?
I'm surprised. I thought one of Himmel's
party members would be...
Would be what?
If anything, you surprised me.
You tried to kill Fern's party
during the first test, didn't you?
Fern complained to me about it.
She said you seemed like someone
who'd kick a dog out of the way.
I get that a lot.
All I did was threaten them.
Though there was one of them whose death
would probably make the world a better place.
I'd do anything to protect my hometown.
I wanted to become a first-class mage for
the privilege of learning any spell I desired.
With a more powerful spell,
I can slaughter more demons.
But even in other parts of the world,
I do everything I can to help people in need.
Why?
My hometown is on the northern frontier.
There are countless stories
about Himmel the Hero there.
The conquest of the Thousand-Mirror Tower.
His battles against Böse the Immortal,
the Seven Sages of Destruction,
and the Hell Emperor Dragon.
When I was a kid, I loved
those adventure stories.
But the village elders hardly
ever talked about them.
They'd talk about how he defeated the monsters
that attacked the village,
or how he guarded some merchant,
or even how he just helped
carry stuff like a porter.
They were hardly impressive.
Just a bunch of boring stories.
That's what I thought, anyway.
But you could tell how happy the village
elders were when they told those stories.
After Himmel the Hero died
and the remaining demons started
acting up, I finally understood.
The Thousand-Mirror Tower, Böse,
the Hell Emperor Dragon,
even the Demon King—none of that
had anything to do with my village.
Everyone had their hands full
just maintaining their everyday life.
If Himmel the Hero
hadn't come to my village,
then I doubt it'd still be there,
whether he saved the world or not.
I see. What are you trying to say?
Those stories of Himmel's less exciting
adventures were what guided me here.
That's all I'm trying to say.
I've been talking for too long.
I'm heading back with those guys.
Frieren, you should treasure
the encounters you have.
Death isn't the only goodbye in this life.
But I guess you already know that.
Frieren, can't you magic us
across one by one?
Then I'd be left all alone on this side.
Himmel, we need to defeat the
Demon King as soon as possible.
What point is there in helping people
in these insignificant ways?
You're right that they're insignificant.
Such deeds won't change the world.
But I won't ignore those in need
right in front of me.
Don't worry, Himmel.
The world has changed.
We'll be granted our privileges tonight,
and we're each allowed to bring guests.
Since we have the opportunity,
let's all go together.
She looks really unhappy about the idea.
I was told we're allowed to bring guests.
I'm sorry, but Ms. Frieren
is prohibited per Ms. Serie.
For the next thousand years,
she is barred from entering any
Continental Magic Association facility.
What exactly did she do to deserve this?
It can't be helped.
I rubbed Serie the wrong way.
She's like a child.
It's not as though
I wanted to be here anyway.
I'll wait outside.
I'll wait outside, too.
Hey.
That's the early evening bell.
They should be done receiving
their privileges soon.
Yeah.
A first-class mage.
The highest level of mage,
of whom fewer than fifty exist.
Fern has grown so much.
In this era, Fern will probably
become a more famous mage than me.
Frieren.
I'm glad.
Me too.
Ms. Frieren.
Who is he?
A member of the Continental Magic Association.
I'm the first-class mage Lernen,
one of Ms. Serie's students.
I'm sorry for the trouble
Ms. Serie has caused you.
It's fine. She's always been like that.
What is it, Frieren?
You can see the fluctuations
in my mana, can't you?
You're incredibly skilled.
This peaceful era doesn't suit you.
You're right. I am an old-fashioned mage
who only knows battle.
Ms. Serie often says the same thing.
If I'd been born during the era in which
we fought the Demon King's forces,
I would've gone down in history
alongside the other famous heroes.
I see. So what do you want from me?
The only one of Ms. Serie's students
whose name is remembered is her first,
the Great Mage Flamme
spoken of in fairy tales.
Once I grow old and die, yet another
proof of her existence will disappear.
I don't want her to be alone in the future,
even if it means going down in infamy
as the killer of the legendary mage Frieren.
I request a duel, Ms. Frieren.
I won't fight you. It'd be a waste of time.
Honestly.
Mages who only know how to fight
can be so awkward.
There's no need for you to go down in history.
Serie will remember you.
One last thing.
This field of flowers was conjured by magic.
So what?
It was my master's favorite spell.
Didn't you call it useless?
Honestly, Flamme was a failure.
Despite all her talent,
she failed to reach my heights.
I taught many students after her.
Most died without ever reaching my level.
But it's strange.
They were students I chose on a whim,
but I can clearly recall each one's
personality and favorite spell.
Frieren, for some reason, I've never
regretted taking on any of my students.
Even if they never made their mark on history.
She can't even tell her own students
how she truly feels.
She truly is a child.
Ms. Frieren.
I received my privilege.
Shall we go, then?
Ms. Frieren, how did you get
that injury on your shoulder?
I'd better get it healed at the church.
Do you think they're still open?
Truly, we are awkward.
Both you and I.
Stark, what are we gonna do today?
Sorry, but I can't play today.
Stark, did you have breakfast this morning?
I already ate.
Stark, have some of this.
Hey, thanks.
The path of the warrior
is long and treacherous.
Take care.
I will.
It's time to say goodbye to Äußerst.
People love you
everywhere you go, Mr. Stark.
Yeah?
By the way, Fern, what spell
did you end up asking for yesterday?
Can't you tell?
Your clothes are clean.
And they smell vaguely floral.
Could it be...
It's a spell to make clothes
clean and spotless.
This will make laundry a breeze.
Serie the Living Grimoire
lived up to her name.
That's a legendary-level spell
from the era of mythology.
Well done, Fern.
That's my student.
Of course, Ms. Frieren.
Ms. Serie didn't seem at all
happy about it, though.
Are you insane?
I'm sure. Serves her right.
They're here.
Frieren, thank you for everything.
We didn't pass this time,
but we'll try again in three years.
I see. That's good.
It's been fun.
Take care.
See you later.
Yeah. See you later.
That was a rather quick goodbye,
just like with Sein.
And Kraft.
Himmel, you always say quick goodbyes.
You think that's strange?
It doesn't seem like you.
It was just a side job, but we still
spent two weeks traveling together.
And we drank with him practically every night.
You corrupt priest.
You're right.
And you alright
But I'm sure we'll run into each other again
if we continue traveling.
Can you hear me
Trailing along deserted train tracks
Tearful goodbyes aren't our style.
Crying excessively
Wanting you to smile
After all, it would be embarrassing
when we met again.
I hold on to memories I'd like to keep fresh
There's something I'd like to tell you
With words more precious than a goodbye
Unremarkable yet special
See, things that couldn't have been
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
Why? They begin to overflow
So, if I were to be born again
I would surely choose this place once more
So, if we were to meet again
I'd never let you go, I'd choose the present
Even if no promises were made
Even if I'm lost in days of loneliness
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
I'm whispering our lullaby
for you to come back home
It would be embarrassing when we met again.
What does that mean?
Episode 28: It Would Be Embarrassing When We Met Again